Richard A. Florsheim Papers
Richard A. Florsheim Papers
1927-1997
Florsheim, Richard A., 1916-1979
17 linear ft.
Primarily correspondence (1927-1979). Also, artwork reproductions; manuscript and printed articles, book reviews, and essays; lecture notes and manuscripts; photographs and memorabilia, including clippings (1951-1979), exhibition catalogs and invitations from the 1940s through the 1980s; and financial material relating to artwork prices and studio construction. Correspondence of greatest depth and duration with Rose H. Alschuler, the Artists Equity Association, Artists League of the Midwest, Illinois Arts Council, Norman MacLeish, José Pijoán, Peter Pollack, Daniel Catton Rich, Rose Valland, and Hudson Walker. Other correspondents include Edgar Britton, Clayton Charles, Leon Kroll, Martyl, Arthur Rissman, and Ladislas Segy.
148983
Biographical History
American Jewish painter, lithographer, lecturer, educator.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning 1927 to 1997, the Richard A. Florsheim Papers comprises correspondence, artwork reproductions, writings, photographs and memorabilia of the American Jewish painter, printmaker, lecturer, and educator. While illuminating Florsheim's personal relationships, the collection principally documents his leadership roles in artists' organizations (e.g. Artists Equity Association, Illinois Arts Council) as well as his gallery affiliations.
Family Correspondence (Boxes 1-2) consists primarily of incoming letters from Florsheim's Chicago industrialist father, his step-mother, step-sister, and brother, in addition to miscellaneous relatives whose correspondence is chronologically arranged.
Encompassing letters, contracts, photographs, receipts, sales records, and a wide variety of printed material, the Correspondence-Subject Files (Boxes 3-29) constitutes the bulk of the collection. Predominantly incoming letters with some outgoing carbons, correspondence of the greatest depth and/or duration consists of that with art associations and organizations (American Artists Group, Artists Equity Association, Associated American Artists, Contemporary Art Workshop, Fine Arts Work Center in Provincetown, Illinois Arts Council, International Association of Plastic Arts, International Graphic Arts Society); art specialists (Jose Pijoan, Peter Pollack, Daniel Catton Rich, Rose Valland, Hudson D. Walker); galleries (Babcock Galleries, Garelick's Gallery, Oehlschlaeger Galleries, Jacques Seligmann Galleries, Shore Galleries, E. and A. Silberman Galleries); and painter Norman H. MacLeish; as well as the Adult Education Council of Greater Chicago, Rose H. Alschuler, Sidney and Rosalie Berkowitz, Motive, National Art Week (1940, 1941), Jeanne C. Rogers, and the United States Navy. Included among these documents is material relating to the U.S. Senate investigation of artists' organizations (Artists Equity Association), Florsheim's work with students (Contemporary Art Workshop), and his contribution as an inventor during World War II (United States Navy).
Other correspondence, much of which documents the art scene in Chicago, Provincetown, New York City, and Woodstock, includes that with artists (Henry Billings, Aaron Bohrod, Edgar Britton, Victor Candell, Clayton Charles, Edward A. Chavez, Jerry and Helen Sawyer Farnsworth, Ernest Fiene, Mary Gehr, Cleve Gray, Davenport Griffen, Philip Guston, Lily Harmon, Murray Jones, Joseph Kaplan, Norman Kent, Rockwell Kent, Leon Kroll, Yasuo and Sara Kuniyoshi, Rico Lebrun, Sidnee Livingston, Ethel Magafan, Boris and Jan Gelb Margo, Martyl, Edward and Norma Millman, Seong Moy, Katherine Nash, William Pachner, Arthur Rissman, Andree Ruellan, Viktor Schreckengost, Ladislas Segy, Kenneth Shopen, Arlie Sinaiko, Mitchell Siporin, Frances Toor, Stuyvesant Van Veen, Emmanuel Viviano, John Edwin and Jano Walley, Ben Wolf, Joseph L. Young); authors (Inez Boulton, Gwendolyn Brooks, Alexander Eliot, Lucy Freeman, Katharine Kuh, Alain Locke, John Frederick Nims, Louis Simpson); composer Roy Harris; dancer Ruth St. Denis; and photographer Arnold Newman.
Reproductions of Florsheim's paintings in the form of promotional material for Associated American Artists and the International Graphic Arts Society, commercial greeting cards, and a book jacket constitute Artwork (Box 30).
Writings (Boxes 30-31) includes manuscript and printed articles, essays, and book reviews; a diary for 1933; a number of lecture manuscripts and notes pertaining to art; Florsheim's self-published "Prose and Verse"; and miscellaneous student papers.
Memorabilia (Box 32) encompasses articles and newspaper clippings about Florsheim (1951-1979); exhibition catalogs and invitations for the 1940s through the 1980s; two exhibition guest registers; an exhibition poster; financial data on artwork prices and studio construction; lecture-related material; and documents related to a trip to Italy.
Photographs (Box 33, Oversize 1) includes pictures from early childhood, formal portraits of Florsheim throughout his life, pictures of his home and studio and with his wife Helen. There are also a number of family photos, including several portraits of Helen Florsheim.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Alschuler, Rose H. (Rose Haas), 1887-1979.; Britton, Edgar, 1901-1982.; Charles, Clayton, 1915-; Florsheim, Richard A., 1916-1979.; Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974.; MacLeish, Norman, 1898-1949.; Martyl, 1917-2013.; Pijoán, José, 1881-1963.; Pollack, Peter, 1909-1978.; Rich, Daniel Catton, 1904-1976.; Rissman, Arthur.; Segy, Ladislas.; Valland, Rose.; Walker, Hudson D. (Hudson Dean), 1907-1976.; Artists Equity Association.; Artists League of the Midwest.; Illinois Arts Council.; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Artist colonies -- Massachusetts -- Provincetown.; Artist colonies -- New York (State) -- Woodstock.; Artists -- Societies, etc.; Artists, Jewish -- United States; Lithographers -- United States; Painters -- United States; Painting, American; Painting, Modern -- 20th century -- United States; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Lectures.; Photographs.; Artists.; Lithographers.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Biographical Material
  - Biographical Material (Box 1)
  - Dick Florsheim: A Neighbor's Memoir, by Richard McKown. Provincetown Arts, 1993. (Box 1)
  - Richard and Helen Florsheim: A Remembrance, by Richard McKown (1997)., typewritten manuscript with photograph (Box 1)
- Family Correspondence
  - Aberle, Dan (cousin), 1953-1957 (Box 1)
  - Duschinsky, Vilma F. and Richard, See Florsheim, Vilma F.
  - Florsheim, Leonard S. (brother), 1942; undated (Box 1)
  - Florsheim, Leonard S. (father)
    - 1936-1938, 1 folder (Box 1)
    - 1940-1964, undated, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Florsheim, Lilliana K. ("Lee" - step-sister), 1944-1963; undated (Box 2)
  - Florsheim, Vilma F. (step-mother), 1943-1977; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Household employees, 1937-1951; undated (Box 2)
  - McNeil, Lucille (father's secretary), 1946-1960; undated (Box 2)
  - Slingerland, Vilma F. and Harold B., See Florsheim, Vilma F.
  - Miscellaneous relatives, 1935-1977; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
- Correspondence-Subject Files
  - A, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Adler, Lee, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Adult Education Council of Greater Chicago, 1949-1972; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Albright, Ivan, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Allcott, John V., 1948 (Box 3)
  - Allison, Bill, 1946; 1948,; 1974,; 1975,; undated (Box 3)
  - Alschuler, Rose H., 1940-1976; undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - American Artist (New York, N.Y.), 1959-1966 (Box 3)
  - American Artists Group, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1946; 1961-1970,; undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union. Chicago Division, 1948 (Box 3)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
  - American Youth Congress (New York, N.Y.), 1934-1935 (Box 3)
  - Amor, Ines, 1939-1946 (Box 3)
  - Anderson, Donald James, 1957-1970; undated (Box 3)
  - Anet, B. and H., 1938-1968; undated (Box 3)
  - Angel, Rifka, [c. 1935]; 1948 (Box 4)
  - Archives of American Art, 1971-1976; undated (Box 4)
    See also Biographical material for interview transcript
  - Arnold, Hillis, 1948 (Box 4)
  - Arose Sales Co. (New York, N.Y.), See Gross, Rose and Jack
  - Arquin, Florence, See Williams, Florence and Sam
  - Art Education Association of Indiana, 1956-1957 (Box 4)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1935-1959 (Box 4)
  - Art Unlimited Gallery (San Francisco, Calif.), 1961 (Box 4)
  - Artists Equity Association
    See also Artists League of the Midwest
    - 1947-1949, 6 folders (Box 4)
    - 1950-1954 Sept., 10 folders (Box 5)
    - 1954 Oct.-1956, 10 folders (Box 6)
    - 1957-1979, 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Artists' League of Chicago, See Artists League of the Midwest
  - Artists League of the Midwest, 1946-1950; undated; 2 folders
    See also Artists Equity Association
  - Artists Union of Chicago, 1936; undated (Box 7)
  - Arts Assembly at the Adult Education Council of Greater Chicago, See Adult Education Council of Greater Chicago
  - Arts Center Association, Inc. (Chicago, Ill.), 1951-1952; 1957,; undated (Box 7)
  - Arts Club of Chicago, 1956-1968 (Box 7)
  - Ashton Gallery (Chestnut Hill, Mass.), 1970-1972; undated (Box 7)
  - Associated American Artists (New York, N.Y.)
    - 1940-1969, 10 folders (Box 8)
    - 1970-1977, undated, 9 folders (Box 9)
  - Atwood and Goldberg (Chicago, Ill.), 1950-1951; undated (Box 9)
  - Avati, Mario and Helen, 1968 (Box 9)
  - B, 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Babcock Galleries (New York, N.Y.)
    - 1958-1962, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1963-1971, undated, 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Bak, Bronislaw M. and Hedi, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Baldinelli, Armando, 1964 (Box 10)
  - Barff, Stafford and Helene, 1962-1975 (Box 10)
  - [F. E.] Barr & Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1945-1947; undated (Box 10)
  - Beck, Margit, undated (Box 10)
  - [Adele] Bednarz Galleries (Los Angeles, Calif.), 1974-1977 (Box 10)
    See also Challis Galleries (Laguna Beach, Calif.)
  - Begner, Edith, 1970-1977 (Box 10)
  - Beloit College (Beloit, Wisc.), 1947-1948; 1959-1960 (Box 10)
    See also Charles, Clayton and Babe
  - Benedek, Therese, 1946 (Box 10)
  - Bentley, Claude and Fran, 1956; 1957,; 1969 (Box 10)
  - Berenson, Bernard, 1950 (Box 10)
  - Berglund, Amanda, 1948 (Box 10)
  - Berio, Luciano, 1969 (Box 10)
  - Berkowitz, Rosalie and Sidney, 1954-1968, (2 folders); undated (Box 10)
  - Berkowitz, William Frost, undated (Box 10)
  - Bernard, Emile, 1937-1938 (Box 10)
  - Biesel, Fred, 1950? (Box 10)
  - Bigar, Muriel and Philippe Paul-Cavallier, 1965-1978; undated (Box 10)
    See also Gallery of Modern Art (Scottsdale, Ariz.)
  - Billings, Henry ("Josh"), 1963; 1971 (Box 10)
  - Birmingham Museum of Art, 1954-1966 (Box 10)
  - [Bob] Blackburn Lithographic Printing (New York, N.Y.), 1948-1952; undated (Box 10)
  - Blanchet, Laure and Louis, 1965; undated (Box 10)
  - Blouet, Louis, 1938 (Box 10)
  - Bobbitt, Vernon L., 1949 (Box 10)
  - Bocour, Leonard, 1968 (Box 10)
  - Bohrod, Aaron and Ruth, 1952-1969; undated (Box 10)
  - Bonsall, Arthur, 1937-1942; undated (Box 10)
  - Boston Public Library, 1954-1957 (Box 10)
  - Boulton, Inez, 1950?, 1952? (Box 10)
  - Brent, Stuart, 1951; undated (Box 10)
  - Bridaham, Lester Burbank and Dorothy, 1939-1962; undated (Box 10)
  - Britton, Edgar and Margaret, 1939-1956; undated (Box 10)
  - Brod, Fritzi, 1934 (Box 10)
  - Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Browne, Rosalind (Mrs. Byron), 1962-1964 (Box 11)
  - Buka, Donald, 1970-1976 (Box 11)
  - Burlin, Paul, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Burnaby Art Society (Burnaby, B.C., Canada), 1962-1964 (Box 11)
  - Burrows, Abe, 1960 (Box 11)
  - Butler, Doris Lane, 1959-1970; undated (Box 11)
  - C, 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Candell, Victor and Clara, 1966-1968 (Box 11)
  - Capricorn Galleries (Bethesda, Md.), 1968-1976 (Box 11)
  - Caravias, Celeste P., 1958; 1960 (Box 11)
  - Carruthers, Helen B., 1936; 1948,; undated (Box 11)
  - Casey, Joseph Thomas, 1939-1977; undated (Box 11)
  - Castellon, Federico and Hilda, 1967 (Box 11)
  - Cavanaugh, Tom R., 1950 (Box 11)
  - Central Bureau for Young America (New York, N.Y.), See American Youth Congress (New York, N.Y.)
  - Challis Galleries (Laguna Beach, Calif.), 1976-1977 (Box 11)
  - Chapman, Margot, 1972-1976; undated (Box 11)
  - Charles, Clayton and Babe, 1944-1953 (Box 11)
  - Chavez, Edward Arcenio, 1955; 1957 (Box 11)
  - Chicago Artists Equity, 1934 (Box 11)
  - Chicago Civil Liberties Committee, 1946 (Box 11)
  - Chicago Outdoor Art Festivals, Inc., 1949-1950; undated (Box 11)
  - Chicago Public Library, 1947-1965 (Box 11)
  - Chicago Society of Artists, Inc., 1947-1957; undated (Box 11)
  - Christ-Janer, Albert, 1949-1966 (Box 11)
    See also Arts Center Association, Inc. (Chicago, Ill.)
  - Clough, Wendell S., 1944-1945; undated (Box 11)
  - Cole, Sylvan and Lillyan, 1962-1972; undated (Box 11)
    See also Associated American Artists (New York, N.Y.)
  - The Contemporaries (New York, N.Y.), 1952-1955; undated (Box 11)
    See also Pratt-Contemporaries Graphic Art Centre (New York, N.Y.)
  - Contemporary Art Workshop (Chicago, Ill.), 1954-1961; undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Corbino, Marcia, 1975-1977; undated (Box 12)
  - Cuneo, Lawrence J., 1952-1959 (Box 12)
  - D, 1 folder (Box 12)
  - Davis, Lew and Mathilde, 1954-1964; undated (Box 12)
  - Debaud, Andree, 1937; undated (Box 12)
  - De Diego, Julio, 1950?-1967 (Box 12)
  - Dehn, Adolf, 1958; 1964 (Box 12)
  - Desow-Fishbein, Lillian, 1959?-1966; undated (Box 12)
  - Devree, Howard, 1949 (Box 12)
  - Dimnet, Ernest, 1937-1954; undated (Box 12)
  - Dorne, Albert, See Famous Artists Schools (New York, N.Y.)
  - Durand-Rose, Andre, 1927-1937; undated (Box 12)
  - Dushkin, David, 1937 (Box 12)
  - E, 1 folder (Box 12)
  - Eliot, Alexander and Jane, 1954-1979; undated (Box 12)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1955 (Box 12)
  - Epstein, Leola and Max, 1943; 1948,; undated (Box 12)
  - Esquire Theater (Chicago, Ill.), 1950 (Box 12)
  - Euler, Frances, 1962-1974 (Box 12)
  - F, 1 folder (Box 12)
  - Famous Artists Schools (New York, N.Y.), 1954 (Box 12)
  - Farnsworth, Jerry and Helen Sawyer, 1966; undated (Box 12)
  - Feher, Georges and Chantal, 1964-1969; undated (Box 12)
  - Fiene, Ernest, 1949; 1950,; 1961 (Box 12)
  - Fine Arts Work Center in Provincetown, Inc., 1968-1974 (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Fisher, Margaret, 1940?, 1945? (Box 12)
  - Fitts, Bill and Kira, 1962-1967; undated (Box 12)
  - Flair Gallery (Cincinnati, Ohio), 1964-1968 (Box 12)
  - Flint Institute of Arts (Flint, Mich.), 1959-1961 (Box 12)
  - Ford Foundation (New York, N.Y.), 1950-1960 (Box 13)
  - Fordon, Sophie, 1962 (Box 13)
  - Fortess, Karl E., 1965; 1967 (Box 13)
  - Foster, Joan, See Burnaby Art Society (Burnaby, B.C., Canada)
  - Frank, Bena Virginia, See Mayer, Bena Frank and Ralph
  - Frapier, Jacques, See Galerie des Peintres Graveurs (Paris, France)
  - Freborg, Stan and Dodie LeCour, 1958?-1966; undated (Box 13)
  - Freeman, Lucy, 1966-1970 (Box 13)
  - Friedlander, Alberta R. and Julius S., 1956-1977; undated (Box 13)
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster, 1949 (Box 13)
  - G, 1 folder (Box 13)
  - Galerie des Peintres Graveurs (Paris, France), 1965-1967 (Box 13)
  - Galerie Gerald Cramer (Geneva, Switzerland), 1952-1958 (Box 13)
  - Galleries of Frank J. Oehlschlaeger (Chicago, Ill.; Sarasota, Fla.), See Oehlschlaeger Galleries (Chicago, Ill.; Sarasota, Fla.)
  - Gallery of Modern Art (Scottsdale, Ariz.), 1964-1969; undated; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Gallery of World Art, Inc. (Newton Center, Mass.), 1966-1970; undated (Box 13)
  - Garelick's Gallery (Detroit, Mich.), 1956-1971; 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Garelick's Gallery (Birmingham, Mich.), 1971-1975 (Box 13)
  - Garelick's Gallery (Scottsdale, Ariz.), 1976-1979 (Box 14)
  - Garrison, Eve, 1950; 1969 (Box 14)
  - Gehr, Mary, 1959?-1970; undated (Box 14)
  - Gelb, Jan, See Margo, Boris and Jan Gelb
  - Gerard, Paula, 1974 (Box 14)
  - Gernand, John, 1944 (Box 14)
  - Gifford, Edwin, 1954-1957; undated (Box 14)
  - Gilmore, Thomas N. and Sally Walker, 1962-1970 (Box 14)
  - Gilot, Francoise, 1964-1965; undated (Box 14)
  - Gitelson, Frances H. and Maxwell, 1957-1971; undated (Box 14)
  - Gogh, V. W. van, 1950-1960; 1972,; 1973,; undated (Box 14)
  - Goldberg, Bertrand and Claire, 1944-1961; undated (Box 14)
    See also Atwood and Goldberg (Chicago, Ill.)
  - Gomez, Giovanni, 1938; 1946 (Box 14)
  - Gonzalez, Xavier and Ethel, 1961 (Box 14)
  - Gray, Cleve, 1954; 1957 (Box 14)
  - Greene, Marie Zoe, 1960-1969; undated (Box 14)
  - Griffen, Davenport, 1935; 1950,; 1968 (Box 14)
  - Gross, Earl, undated (Box 14)
  - Gross, Rose and Jack, 1962-1976; undated (Box 14)
  - Grossberg, Herbert, 1941; undated (Box 14)
  - [John Simon] Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1944-1950 (Box 14)
  - Guiramand, Paul, 1962-1969; undated (Box 14)
  - Guston, Philip, undated (Box 14)
  - H, 1 folder (Box 14)
  - Haas, Terry?, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Halpert, Edith Gregor, 1953-1957 (Box 14)
  - Harmon, Lily, 1959; undated (Box 14)
  - Harris, Roy and Johana, 1950-1956; undated (Box 14)
  - Harris, Sydney J., 1950; 1955 (Box 14)
  - Harvey, Laura Cornell, 1948 (Box 14)
  - Hawker, Anthony, 1937 (Box 14)
  - Hawthorne, Joseph, 1957-1969 (Box 14)
  - Haydon, Harold, See Artists Equity Association; Artists League of the Midwest
  - Heer, Joyce, 1966-1967 (Box 14)
  - Heller, Bonnie, 1956-1964; undated (Box 14)
  - Henner, Edna Wolff, 1948; 1956 (Box 14)
  - Heron, Michael W. and Hatty Walker, 1960-1970; undated (Box 14)
  - Herzog, E. (Betsy), 1946-1951; undated (Box 14)
  - Heydenryk, Henry, 1958-1968 (Box 14)
  - Himmelfarb, Samuel, 1954; 1958 (Box 14)
  - Hodgman, Crosby and Donna, 1962; 1974 (Box 14)
  - Hondius, Paula, undated (Box 14)
  - Horn, John S., 1937-1942; undated (Box 14)
  - [Bernard] Horwich Jewish Community Center. Advisory Art Committee (Chicago, Ill.), 1962-1971 (Box 14)
  - Howland, Carol and Richard Hubbard, 1935? (Box 14)
  - Mari Huebsch Galleries (Woodstock, N.Y.), 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - I, 1 folder (Box 14)
  - Illinois Art Education Association, 1955 (Box 14)
  - Illinois Arts Council, See also Weber, John
    - 1965-1969 [II], 21 folders (Box 15)
    - 1969 [III]-1971, 18 folders (Box 16)
    - 1972-1973, 10 folders (Box 17)
  - Illinois Institute of Technology, 1956-1957 (Box 18)
  - Illinois Sesquicentennial Commission, 1966-1967 (Box 18)
  - Instituto Nacional de Bellas Artes (Mexico), 1951-1953; undated (Box 18)
  - International Association of Plastic Arts, 1954; 1960-1963, (3 folders); undated (Box 18)
  - International Graphic Arts Society, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1952-1959; undated; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Irwin, George M., See Illinois Arts Council
  - J, 1 folder (Box 18)
  - James, Bertha Ten Eyck, See Rich, Daniel Catton and Bertha
  - James, William, 1936 (Box 18)
  - Jemerin, Edward E., 1959-1969 (Box 18)
  - Jewish Community Centers of Chicago, See [Bernard] Horwich Jewish Community Center. Advisory Art Committee (Chicago, Ill.) (Box 18)
  - Jones, Murray and Janet, 1946-1949; undated (Box 18)
  - Jules, Mervin, 1957; 1964 (Box 18)
  - K, 1 folder (Box 18)
  - Kabo Corset Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1941-1952; undated (Box 18)
  - Kallen, Horace Meyer, 1943-1974 (Box 18)
  - Kamys, Walter, 1958 (Box 18)
  - Kaplan, Joseph and Virginia, 1958-1966; undated (Box 18)
  - Kaplan, Stanley A. and Joan, 1968; 1974-1977 (Box 18)
  - Kapner, Elizabeth, undated (Box 18)
  - Kapstein, Dorothy M. and John J., 1957-1976; undated (Box 18)
  - Kaufman, Florence and Nancy, 1937-1939 (Box 18)
  - Kent, Norman, 1966-1968 (Box 19)
    See also American Artist (New York, N.Y.)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1946-1955 (Box 19)
  - Kessler, Marian, 1975; 1977,; undated (Box 19)
  - King, Nettie, 1949-1950 (Box 19)
  - Kirby, Glo, undated (Box 19)
  - Kirkland, Wallace, 1957?, 1961 (Box 19)
  - Klein, Ernest L., 1950-1951; 1958 (Box 19)
  - Kleinholz, Frank, 1956-1963 (Box 19)
  - Klimpert, Rudi, 1958; 1964-1969 (Box 19)
  - Kremer, William, 1944-1945 (Box 19)
  - Kroll, Leon, 1948-1965; undated (Box 19)
  - Kuh, Katharine, 1956-1959?; 1976,; undated (Box 19)
  - Kuniyoshi, Yasuo and Sara, 1949-1958; undated (Box 19)
  - L, 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Lacouriere, Roger, 1953-1956 (Box 19)
  - LaGorce, Louise, undated (Box 19)
  - Lake County Art League (Waukegan, Ill.), 1949 (Box 19)
  - Landau Gallery (Los Angeles, Calif.), 1954-1959 see also (Box 19)
    See also Family Correspondence: Aberle, Dan
  - Langsdorf, Martyl Schweig and Alexander, See Martyl
  - Lasswell, Harold Dwight, 1947-1952 (Box 19)
  - Lawrence, Robert, 1950-1952; undated (Box 19)
  - Layton School of Art (Milwaukee, Wisc.), 1969 (Box 19)
  - Lebrun, Rico, 1952?, 1956 (Box 19)
  - Lee, Doris, 1955; undated (Box 19)
  - Leo, Ralph C. and Hope, 1940-1948; undated (Box 19)
  - Leon, Joseph, 1957; 1962,; undated (Box 19)
  - Lersy, Roger and Janine, 1964-1969; undated (Box 19)
  - Lewis, Harvey Alvin, 1950-1961; undated (Box 19)
  - Lexington Gallery (Lexington, Mass.), See Ashton Gallery (Chestnut Hill, Mass.)
  - [Republic of] Liberia. Centennial Commission, 1946-1947 (Box 19)
  - [Leonard] Linn Inc. (Winnetka, Ill.), 1949-1952 (Box 19)
  - Little Gallery (Chicago, Ill.), 1958-1962; undated (Box 19)
  - Livingston, Sidnee, 1948-1958 (Box 19)
  - Locke, Alain LeRoy, 1946; 1949,; undated (Box 19)
  - Lowengrund, Margaret, See The Contemporaries (New York, N.Y.)
  - Lukosh, June, 1950 (Box 19)
  - Lustigman, Lisa, 1972-1977; undated (Box 19)
  - [Joseph] Luyber Galleries (New York, N.Y.), 1946-1950; undated (Box 19)
  - M, 1 folder (Box 19)
  - Mack, Gerstle, 1937 (Box 19)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1976 (Box 19)
  - MacLeish, Norman H.
    - 1934-1936, 1 folder (Box 19)
    - 1937-1969, 6 folders (Box 20)
  - Magafan, Ethel, 1954-1965 (Box 20)
  - Malamed, Daniel S., 1977 (Box 20)
  - Malicoat, Philip and Barbara, 195?-1969 (Box 20)
  - Manaranche, Alexis and Madeleine, 1963-1969 (Box 20)
  - Mandel, Howard, 1955-1964; telegrams (Box 20)
  - Mandel Brothers Art Exhibition Galleries (Chicago, Ill.), 1948-1955; undated (Box 20)
  - Mansfield State College (Mansfield, Pa.), 1962-1964 (Box 20)
  - Marantz, Irving, 1959 (Box 20)
  - Margo, Boris and Jan Gelb, 1955-1961; undated (Box 20)
  - Maril, Herman, 1959 (Box 20)
  - Martha's Vineyard Art Association, 1962; 1965,; undated (Box 20)
  - Martyl, 1955-1975; undated (Box 20)
  - Maschgan, Edna Wolff, See Henner, Edna Wolff
  - Mayer, Bena Frank and Ralph, 1964; undated (Box 20)
  - Mayer, Milton and Jane, 1950-1961 (Box 20)
  - McClellan, John, 1955; 1963 (Box 20)
  - McCrae, Gordon H., 1937-1951 (Box 20)
  - Meeker, Dean, 1956 (Box 20)
  - Mermin, Mildred Shire, 1964; undated (Box 20)
  - Midwest College Art Conference (University of Wisconsin-Madison), 1959 (Box 20)
  - Milles, Carl, 1941 (Box 20)
  - Millman, Edward and Norma, 1941-1955 (Box 20)
  - Millsaps, Daniel, 1957 (Box 20)
  - Minaux, Andre, 1953; 1967,; undated (Box 20)
  - Monogram of California, 1954 (Box 20)
  - Montane, Roger, 1955; 1967 (Box 20)
  - Motive (Nashville, Tenn.), 1947-1950; 1953 (2 folders) (Box 21)
  - Moy, Seong, 1956-1964 (Box 21)
  - N, 1 folder (Box 21)
  - Nash, Katherine, 1949; 1959 (Box 21)
  - National Art Week, 1940; 1941, (2 folders); undated (Box 21)
  - Neal, Reginald, 1954-1959; undated (Box 21)
  - Neiman, Lilyan, 1946; 1947,; undated (Box 21)
  - [Elizabeth] Nelson Galleries (Chicago, Ill.), 1950-1954; undated (Box 21)
  - Netzorg, Ruth and Anna, 1942; undated (Box 21)
  - Neumeyer, Alfred, 1949; 1951 (Box 21)
  - Nevinny, Hans B., 1969-1970 (Box 21)
  - New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.), 1943; 1944,; undated (Box 21)
  - Newhauser, Herman, 1945 (Box 21)